softcomplex.com 2005-12-12

# Softcomplex - Privacy Policy

## Table of Contents

  * Our Commitment to Privacy
  * Web Server's Log File
  * Support Forum
  * Product Ordering
  * Technical Support
  * Online Services
  * Newsletter subscription
  * Illegal Software Usage Tracking
  * Employee Access to Customer Information
  * Specific content and Kid's privacy
  * Compliance with Legal Process
  * What Are Cookies?
  * External Links
  * Accessing and Changing Your Information
  * Contacting Us
  * Related Links

## Our Commitment to Privacy

Here at Softcomplex we take your privacy seriously and we want you to be aware of any information we collect and the ways we use it. These are our basic guidelines to customers' privacy:

  * We collect only minimum information required to deliver high quality products and/or services customer is interested in 
  * We avoid any annoying practices related to customers' privacy even if they promise high profits 
  * We respect freedom of choice so we ask for permission before doing something that customer may not like 

We do our best to make your business with us smooth and comfortable. Don't hesitate to contact us should you have any suggestions or complaints.

## Web Server's Log File

As any other web site softcomplex.com keeps the record of all requests made and processed. This helps us maintain server and web site, analyze visitors activity, find broken links, optimize interfaces and code of our web applications and investigate security related issues. For you this means high speed, 24/7 reliable access to online resources and nice looking, easy to navigate pages.

Each record in server's log contains the following data:

  * Date and Time
  * Client's IP address
  * Request Method
  * Resource requested
  * Protocol and version
  * Response Code
  * Size of the response
  * Client's software (User Agent)

Note that log records contain no personal data.

## Support Forum

[Support forum](http://www.softcomplex.com/forum/ "Click to visit Softcomplex support forum \(opens in new window\)") is interactive constantly growing knowledge base that customers use to find answers to products related questions and discuss their challenges. No registration is required to read postings in the forum. Customers should create account in order to post messages in the forum. We neither share this information with anyone nor use it for any purposes not related to the forum. Registration form contains the following fields: 

  * **Username** \- required, must be unique 
  * **E-Mail** \- required, your password will be send to this address upon successful registration 
  * Site - optional 
  * Aim - optional 
  * ICQ - optional 
  * Yahoo - optional 
  * MSN - optional 
  * Location - optional 
  * Birthday - optional (also see Kid's privacy section) 
  * Bio - optional 

When you post the message in the forum your registration information can be accessed by other visitors. If you don't want to disclose this information you can leave optional fields blank. E-mail address can be removed after the registration using profile editor of the forum. Removing your email address from the profile will also disable any e-mail notifications that forum supports (i.e. notification about new posting in some particular topic).

As long as information you post can be accessed by other visitors make sure you don't provide in your messages any personal information such as passwords, secret URLs, license information etc.

Other members can contact you using 'user to user messaging' feature of the forum. These messages will be shown to you only when you login to the forum (no e-mails are sent). Make use of 'ignore list' if you don't want to receive message from particular member.

Forum uses Cookies for personalization features such as: 'New posts in this forum since last active' and for session tracking when you are logged in.

## Product Ordering

Softcomplex receives online orders via well known and trusted payment options:

  * PayPal [[read privacy policy](http://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=p/gen/ua/policy_privacy-outside "PayPal")]
  * ShareIt [[read privacy policy](http://www.shareit.com/privacy_statement.html "ShareIt")]

Customers are forwarded to secure servers of payment operator to complete the purchase. Secure Socket Layer protocol is used to protect the data you submit from any unauthorized access.

From payment operator we only receive registration related information, we have no access to credit card numbers or bank account details you provided during purchase. License registration details are stored in our database for further references. Each record includes:

  * Order ID
  * Registration Name
  * Contact E-mail
  * Product and license type
  * Quantity of the licenses purchased
  * Date of registration

We use this information while providing support to customers and when investigating licensing violation issues.

## Technical Support

Technical information obtained while we provide support may be used to train personnel and to create documentation, knowledge base, FAQs and other support materials. No personal information of customer will be published.

## Online Services

Softcomplex offers online services such as [Tigra Menu Online Builder](http://www.javascriptmenubuilder.com/ "Tigra Menu Online Builder"). Some online services require registration so data you enter while operating application is password protected from unauthorized access. Any information collected by online applications we offer is not disclosed to third parties and it is not used for any purposes not directly related to the functions of the application.

## Newsletter subscription

You may be interested in receiving notifications about new products released and about updates available for existing products. When subscription form is submitted we'll send verification message to insure that correct contact information provided and request is send by the owner of the address. We don't send more than one newsletter per month. Reason for mailing and unsubscribe instructions are provided at the top of each message. Removal requests are processed and confirmed immediately upon reception.

Softcomplex newsletter does not advertise third party products or services. Information about subscribers is not shared with any third parties.

## Illegal Software Usage Tracking

Free products and legally purchased commercial products do not disclose customer's privacy in any way. There is no 'spy ware' functions embedded into the code. Commercial products being illegally used may display warning messages and send reports to our server. We'll investigate all cases of pirated software usage.

## Employee Access to Customer Information

Our corporate values, ethical standards, policies and practices are committed to the protection of customer information. In general, our business practices limit employee access to confidential information, and limit the use and disclosure of such information to authorized persons, processes and transactions.

## Specific content and Kid's privacy

All materials Softcomplex creates are safe for persons of any age including kids. Also no political, cultural, religious or any other preferences are ever expressed in the content offered.

Visitors are never required to specify age information. Parents should advice kids to leave age and/or birth date fields blank.

## Compliance with Legal Process

We may disclose personal information if we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to:

  1. comply with the law or with legal process;
  2. protect and defend our rights and property;
  3. protect against misuse or unauthorized use of Softcomplex on the Web
  4. protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public (among other things, this means that if you provide false information or attempt to pose as someone else, information about you may be disclosed as part of any investigation into your actions).

## What Are Cookies?

Cookies are a standard feature of Web browser software that allows Web servers to recognize the computer used to access a Web site. Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored by a user�s Web browser on the user�s hard drive. Cookies can remember what information a user accesses on one Web page to simplify subsequent interactions with that Web site by the same user or to use the information to streamline the user�s transactions on related Web pages. This makes it easier for a user to move from Web page to Web page and to complete commercial transactions over the Internet. Cookies should make your online experience easier and more personalized.

## External Links

Our site may contain links to other web sites. We're not responsible for the content or privacy practices of those sites.

## Accessing and Changing Your Information

In most cases you can review and update your personal information using the same application you submitted it with. Contact us in case you experience difficulties finding or updating your records at Softcomplex.

## Contacting US

Don't hesitate to [contact us](http://www.softcomplex.com/support.html "contact Softcomplex in the way that is most convenient for you") should you have any questions, concerns, suggestions or complaints related to the ways we protect your privacy. Your feedback is very important for us. Variety of ways is available for communication.

## Related Links

Internal Links:

  * [**Softcomplex Homepage**](http://www.softcomplex.com/ "visit our homepage and learn more about our company") \- visit our homepage and learn more about Softcomplex
  * [**Web Site User Agreement**](http://www.softcomplex.com/site_agreement.html "Softcomplex.com web site user agreement") \- information related to use of softcomplex.com and responsibilities
  * [**Newsletter**](http://www.softcomplex.com/newsletter/ "be notified about new product releases, updates and discounts we offer") \- be notified about new product releases, updates and discounts we offer
  * [**Support Forum**](http://www.softcomplex.com/forum/ "find answers to your technical questions, share your code and discuss your challenges with other customers") \- find answers to your technical questions, share your code and discuss your challenges with other customers
  * [**Contact US**](http://www.softcomplex.com/support.html "contact Softcomplex in the way that is most convenient for you") \- contact Softcomplex in the way that is most convenient for you

External Links:

  * [**Web Log**](http://httpd.apache.org/docs/mod/mod_log_config.html "learn about information that web server collects") \- learn about information that web server collects
  * [**SSL**](http://wp.netscape.com/security/techbriefs/ssl.html "learn about secure socket layer") \- learn about secure socket layer
